原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     累
校对     累
时间轴     西·查
后期     累
总监     累
用力  用力
Push, push.
我晚点回来
I'll be home late.
好早啊
It's so early.
是啊  今天事很多
Yeah. It's gonna be a long day.
你看起来好憔悴
You look torn.
你去是上班
Should you go to work...
还是躺在我身上
Or should you lie on top of me?
我没那么有福气  早上和你做爱
God don't like me enough to give me you in the morning
还能过一个宁静的下午
and a peaceful afternoon in the same day.
你想早上和我做爱
Me in the morning...
还是有一个宁静的下午
or peace in the afternoon.
这是个艰难的选择
That's a tough choice.
人家真的不知道该怎么选呢
I'd hate to be in your shoes.
黄石
第三季  第七集
担保契约
别起来  待多久都可以
Don't get up. Stay as long as you want.
靠  我也想骑烈马把后背摔坏
Hey, baby, I wish some bronc'd break my back
这样我就可以躺在床上一直干到中午了
so I could lay in bed all day bumping fuckin' uglies 'til noon.
听起来不错吧
Don't that sound nice?
-迟早啊  -不可能
- Just a matter of time. - It ain't happening.
百分百的事
It's one hundred percent happening.
瞧  凌晨三点看到这画面  辣不辣眼睛
See? This is how you get your eyeball poked out at three in morning.
工棚什么时候变成天堂岛了
When the fuck did the bunkhouse become Paradise Island?
博伊德  开什么玩笑
C'mon, Boyd. You've got to be kidding me.
她这个年纪都能投票  买子弹了
She's old enough to vote and buy bullets.
她眼光不好  你别怪我啊
Don't be blaming me for her bad judgment .
把这些绕桶赛手弄走
Get these goddam barrel racers out of here
免得整个工棚的人
before the whole bunkhouse is carrying
都拿着梳妆袋去竞技场
their groomed bag to the rodeo
像喂混蛋一样喂他们的香肠热狗
and feeding their sausage dogs like fucking assholes.
我们不是吃白食的
We're not freeloaders.
如果你想让我们工作  我们可以工作
If you want to put us to work, we can work.
吉米  精神点  你今天跟我走
Jimmy, get your shit together. You're with me today.
把五岁的栗色马从马厩牵出来
Go get that 5 year-old sorrel out of that stall.
我来
I'll get him.
你带它去哪
Where you taking him?
我懒得用这匹马进行竞技比赛了
I'm tired of trying to ride the rodeo out of this son of a bitch.
我送它去汉密尔顿  它在那里想怎么弓背都行
I'm taking him to Hamilton. He can buck all he wants there.
我能去吗
Can I come?
不行  这不是公路旅行
No, it's not a fucking road trip.
他伤得太重  帮不了你
He's too busted up to help you.
我可以帮忙
I can help.
不用她  我只是
She doesn't have to do that. I'm just being...
那是谁  吉米
Who is that, Jimmy?
米娅  她是我女朋友
It's, uh, Mia. She's my girlfriend.
烦心事又来了
This is gonna be one of these fucking days, isn't it?
真是不想面对啊
I should have never got out of bed.
快上车
Go get your ass in the truck.
你们想听什么
What do y'all want to listen to?
空调
The air conditioning.
-不听音乐吗  -不听
- No music? - No music.
沉默寡言型  我喜欢
Strong silent type. I like it.
看来他用了狗
Looks like he used dogs.
用嵌板搭了条小路
Made an alley with panels.
看起来像母牛和小牛
Looks like cows and calves.
我打电话给销售谷仓
I'll call the sale barn.
你给小牛烙印了吗
Did you brand those calves yet?
耳牌
Ear tags?
没有
Nothing.
如果他够聪明  就会改了牛的烙印
Well, if he's smart, he'll change the brand on those cows
开车送去北达科他州
and drive 'em to North Dakota.
但他肯定想现在就卖掉那些小牛
But he's gonna wanna sell those calves right now.
莱恩  你负责三叉市的销售谷仓
Ryan, why don't you take the sale barn in Three Forks.
你负责刘易斯顿  我负责比林斯
You take Lewiston, I'll take Billings.
我是牲畜委员会的亨顿探员
This is livestock agent Hendon.
我能和拍卖经理谈谈吗
May I speak to the auction manager?
没有找到更改约翰·达顿
There's no court filing that changes Power of Attorney
名下农场委托书的法庭文件
for the Dutton ranch for John Dutton.
那她就是利用舒瓦茨和梅耶公司的律师
Well, then she used Schwartz and Meyers attorneys
在盐湖城提交了
and they filed it in Salt Lake.
那在这里就无效了吗
Does that make it invalid here?
不是  但这样就把水搅浑了
No, but it does muddy the water.
对了  选举部门需要一份
Oh and, elections division needs a certified copy
你出生证明的核证副本
of your birth certificate.
好的  没问题
Okay, that's fine.
我不能签字  必须是你
I can't sign for it. Has to be you.
你在楼下就可以签字
They can get it for you downstairs.
能等到会议结束吗
Can it wait until after the meeting?
他们说必须存档才能批准你的任命
They said it must be on file to ratify your appointment.
我觉得他们想在会议前搞定
I think they want it done before the meeting.
好吧
Okay.
驾照和社保卡
Driver's license and Social Security card?
舒瓦茨和梅耶
Schwartz and Meyer?
是的
Yep.
-我们不是换了  -是的
- Didn't we replace-- - Yep.
我会用双层玻璃
You know, I'd double pane that.
我也是这么想的
Was thinking the same thing.
好主意  伙计  英雄所见略同
Great minds, buddy. Great minds.
你最近好像经常这样
Seem to be doing a lot of that lately.
经常什么
A lot of what?
放空自己
Whole lot of staring into nothing.
我需要时间来做出决定
I have decisions to make that take time.
我得好好想想
Take a lot of thought.
这世界变化得太快了  亲爱的
The world just got a little too fast, honey.
我们得想办法让它慢下来
We need to find a way to slow it down.
世界好像并不会慢下来  爸
Not sure the world does slow down, Dad.
只要知道方法就可以
It does if you know how.
那我得好好学一下
You're going to have to teach me that trick.
你要嫁给他  是吗
You're going to marry him, aren't you?
也许吧
Maybe.
只要他向我求婚
If he asks me.
是的
Yes.
他不会的  亲爱的
He won't ask you, honey.
为什么
Why not?
不是因为他不想
Not because he doesn't want to,
而是因为他永远不会询问我的意思
but because he'll never ask me for your hand,
如果他不问我  就肯定不会向你求婚
and he'll never ask you without doing that.
因为他不想让我为难
He wouldn't want to put me in that position,
虽然我根本不会为难
even though he isn't putting me anywhere.
但他不会的  亲爱的  所以如果你想嫁
He just won't do it, honey, so if it's what you want
那你就得主动一点
you're gonna have to do the asking yourself.
你是说你不介意吗
Are you saying you'd be okay with that?
你是在问我的意思吗
Are you asking me to be okay with it?
他能娶我吗  爸
Can he have my hand, Daddy?
你爱他吗
Do you love him?
你开心吗
Makes you happy?
我对他一见钟情
Since the moment I met him.
既然这样
Well, hap--
你开心就好  亲爱的
Happy is all I've ever wanted for you, sweetheart.
只要他能让你开心  那你就嫁给他吧
You... Give him your hand if he gives you that.
谢谢你  爸爸
Thank you, Daddy.
对不起  贝丝
I'm sorry, Beth.
对不起什么
Sorry for what?
你觉得自己不能来找我
That you thought you couldn't come to me.
你以为我会觉得丢人
That you thought I'd be ashamed or
或者会因此惹上麻烦
you'd be in trouble for it or
随便你是怎么想的
whatever you thought.
你发生了任何事
I am the one safe person in this world
都可以来找我  贝丝
that you can turn to, Beth, for anything.
之前我没有让你感受到  我真的很难过
And it breaks my heart I didn't make you know that.
我现在知道了
I know it now.
当下才是最重要的
And now is all that matters.
你害我费了不少的劲啊
Boy, you made me work for this one.
是吗  为什么
Oh, yeah? How'd I do that?
你没告诉我你是领养的啊
You didn't tell me you were adopted.
因为我不是啊
Because I'm not.
蒙大拿州公共卫生局
詹姆斯·迈克·兰德尔  出生日期1979年5月12日
这不是我
This isn't me.
蒙大拿州民事登记局
收养记录
詹姆斯·迈克·达顿
詹姆斯·迈克·达顿现名詹姆斯·迈克·兰德尔
1979年5月12日出生于蒙大拿州博兹曼市
这他妈是什么
What the fuck is this?
我明确放弃孩子的诉讼通知权
终止我的亲权并将永久法律监护权交于约翰·达顿和伊芙琳·达顿
你是被领养的
You were adopted.
我帮你节省了三天时间
I'm gonna save you three days on the internet
上网查询你家人为什么骗你
trying to figure why your family lied to you.
所以我才花了这么久
This is what took me so long.
这是刑事法庭的记录
This is a criminal court record.
蒙大拿州  兰德尔
原告       被告
被判二级谋杀罪
什么
What...
罪行
杀人  袭击
什么
What...
案情梗概
菲利斯·兰德尔的尸体
有关部门逮捕了加勒特·兰德尔
我干这行学到了一件事
One thing I've learned behind this desk?
大多数人都相信自己在做正确的事
Most people believe they're doing the right thing.
哪怕他们并没有
Even though they ain't.
这件事不能太怪你爸
I wouldn't go too hard on your dad on this one.
换做是我  也不会告诉你的
I wouldn't want you to know that either.
现在没空
Not now.
-但这次会议  -现在没空
- But the meeting... - Not now.
等等
Wait.
联系监狱管理局
Contact the Bureau of Prisons,
看看这个人是否被假释了
find out if this man has been paroled.
如果被假释了  我要他的地址  电话
If he has, I want his address, his phone number,
工作地点之类的  好吗
his place of employment and everything, okay?
好的  我马上去办
Okay, I'll get right on it.
哈佛大学
詹姆斯·迈克·达顿
你他妈是谁
Who the fuck are you?
里普  你的夹克哪买的
Hey Rip, where'd you get your jacket?
默多克吧  在迪伦
The Murdoch's, I believe, in Dillon.
是费尔森牌的吗
Is it a Filson?
-我也不知道  -看起来有点像
- I don't know. - I mean, it kinda looks like a Filson.
我真的很喜欢那种短夹克
I really like them short jackets like that.
女生穿会性感吗
They look hot on a girl?
你们知道我觉得什么叫性感吗
Ya know what I think looks hot?
女生把夹克当衬衫穿
When a girl wears a jacket like it's a shirt.
里面什么都没有  只有夹克
Like, nothing underneath, just the jacket.
我觉得很性感
I think that's sexy.
你们仔细想想  当男人穿着
If you think about it, it's sexy when men wear
应该穿的衣服时就很性感
exactly what they're supposed to wear,
但对女生来说  穿不该穿的衣服才叫性感
but for girls it's sexy to wear what you're not supposed to wear.
我也搞不懂  为什么呢
I don't know. I wonder why that is.
可能是禁忌的魅力吧
I guess it's the taboo of it, ya know?
天啊  这是克里·凯利马刺
Oh shit, these are Kerry Kelley spurs!
我打赌这些混蛋
Woo, I bet these sons of bitches
肯定在谷仓小巷一路高歌
sing all the way down the barn alley.
我靠  这个必须买
God damn. You need to get you some of these.
多少钱
How much are they?
一千吧
They're like a thousand dollars.
一千块
Thousand dollars.
便宜没好货  好货不便宜  好吗
Hey, cool shit ain't cheap and cheap shit ain't cool, okay?
克里·凯利马刺  鲍勃·马尔斯马鞍
Some Kerry Kelley spurs, and a Bob Marrs saddle...
就算不是牛仔  装上这些看起来都像
You may not be a cowboy, but by God you'll look like one.
如果在荒岛上
If y'all were on a desert island
余生只能听一首歌
and could only listen to one song
你们会听什么
for the rest of your life, what would it be?
记住  那首歌会没日没夜地播放
And remember, that son of a bitch is gonna play
就像该死的暴风雨一样
twenty-four-seven from the heavens like a fucking rain storm.
我会选《乌龟漫步》
I would choose "Turtles All the Way Down"
斯特吉尔·辛普森的歌
by Sturgill Simpson, personally.
我可以赤身裸体躺在沙滩上
Man, I'd lay buck-ass naked on the sand
听着这首歌  祈祷救援船永远也找不到我
and listen to that song and pray the rescue boat never finds me.
你知道那首歌吗  里普
You know that song, Rip?
什么歌
What song?
《乌龟漫步》
"Turtles All the Way Down?"
我放给你听  你会喜欢的
Let me play it for ya, you're gonna love it.
好吧  米娅  还是放点音乐吧
Yes, Mia, you know what? Put on some music.
挺好的吧  吉米
Won't that be nice, Jimmy?
还是放点音乐比较好吧
Some music would be nice, wouldn't it?
我发誓  你会喜欢的
I swear, you're going to love it.
-嗯  -*我见过耶稣玩火*
- Right. - *I've seen Jesus play with flames*
*我站在火湖里*
*In a lake of fire I was standing in*
过来  过来
Hey, come here. Come here.
回农场以后  我就杀了你
When we get back to the ranch, I'm gonna kill you.
我亲手杀了你  吉米
With my bare fucking hands, Jimmy.
我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you for this.
*又一次见到佛祖*
*Met Buddha yet another time*
*向我展示了内心的光芒*
*Showed me a glowing light within*
舒瓦茨和梅耶
你不是搬去盐湖城了吗
I thought you moved to Salt Lake.
是的  然后我搬到了这里
I did. Then I moved here.
受够洛杉矶了
Had enough of L.A., huh.
是啊  大胡子嬉皮士都开始骑滑板车上班了
Yeah, when bearded hipsters started riding scooters to work
我就逃出来了  我讨厌那个地方
I got the fuck out of there. I hate that place.
这个市场股票
This Market Equities thing.
真是个难题
It's a real pickle.
你在给他们当顾问吗
Are you advising them now?
主席
The Chairman.
我们的立场相同
We find ourselves on the same side.
真的吗
Really?
这下有意思了
Oh, this could be interesting.
你认识威拉·海斯吗
Do you know Willa Hayes?
我没见过她
I've never met her.
她可不好对付
You have a tiger by the tail with that one.
他们栽在我手里过
I've grabbed them before.
她会害你被炒鱿鱼的  你知道的  对吧
She's going to get you fired. You know that, right?
想摆脱我可没那么容易
I'm pretty hard to get rid of.
那你哥呢  他可信吗
What about your brother? Can he be trusted?
哪怕我在沙漠  也不会从那混蛋手里买水
I wouldn't buy water from that motherfucker if I was in the desert.
明白
Good to know.
要想赢  我们就得玩阴的
To win this, we're going to have to get dirty.
我一直很阴
I stay dirty.
那就好
Good.
这里周末有牛仔竞技  吉米
There's rodeo on the weekends, Jimmy,
有人以竞技为生
there's rodeo for a living,
还有商业竞技
and then there's business rodeo.
这里就是商业竞技
This here is the business rodeo.
怎么了
What's going on?
你们有竞技马吗
You boys got a rank one, huh?
是的  把它放哪
Yep. Where you want him at?
送到竞技场吧
Drop him off in the arena.
我们把它放进马栏  瞧瞧它的本事
We'll stick him in the chute and see what he can do.
好的
All righty.
天啊  那是希德·斯坦纳
Holy shit, that's Sid Steiner.
你见过世界冠军吗  吉米
Ever met a world champion before, Jimmy?
现在你见到了
Now you have.
这小子今年要参加职业比赛吗
Boy going pro this year?
后年
Year after next.
他参加高中牛仔竞技赛了吗
He messing around with those high school rodeos?
没有  里普
Naw, Rip.
我们等他能参加大赛再说
We're going to hold off until he can take a shot at the big show.
到时候大家就知道他的本事了
That's when they'll find out what he's made of.
准备好了吗
You ready?
继续战斗  继续战斗  继续战斗
Keep fighting, keep fighting, keep fighting!
继续
Keep going!
继续战斗  下来
Keep fighting. Get off.
天啊
Jesus.
真是个好牛仔
There's a good cowboy.
你觉得怎么样
Well, what do you think?
弓背挺厉害  里普  但这不是竞技马
He bucks pretty good, Rip, but he's no rodeo horse.
最多几千块吧
I'll give you a few grand for him,
这也是看在你的面子上
but that's just because it's you.
老板只是不想让它浪费粮食了
Boss just wants him off the feed bill.
我也不能坑你啊
I don't want to slap him on yours.
这样吧  我们可以继续驯它
Tell you what, we can keep getting on him
直到它不再反抗  你觉得可以吗
'til he doesn't want to buck anymore if that helps you any.
我来处理吧  谢谢你  希德
I'll take care of it. I appreciate it, Sid.
谢谢  里普
Appreciate you, Rip.
他不想要那匹马吗
He didn't want the horse?
弓背还不够猛
Don't buck hard enough for 'em.
等等  他说那匹马弓背不够猛吗
Wait, he's saying that horse doesn't buck hard enough?
显然啊  吉米  走吧
Evidently not, Jimmy. Let's go.
吉米
Jimmy.
那匹马把农场的所有人都甩下来过
That horse bucked off everyone at the ranch.
我被它甩过两次
Already bucked me off twice.
那个叫斯坦纳的孩子却粘的像创可贴一样
That Steiner kid stuck to it like a fucking Band-Aid.
是啊
Yeah.
那孩子四岁开始骑羊  吉米
That boy's been riding sheep since when he was four, Jimmy.
七岁开始阉牛
Steers since he was seven.
更不用说  他家有三个世界冠军教他
Not to mention, he's got three world champions in his family to teach him.
但他还是可能会死
And he could still die.
我希望你好好考虑一下
I want you to think about that.
你这是干嘛
What is this?
怎么  你这是在叫我别参加牛仔竞技吗
What, this is your way of telling me not to rodeo?
这是我告诉你不该参加竞技的原因
It's my way of showing you why you shouldn't.
你准备怎么办  吉米
What you do with what I show you, Jimmy?
就看你自己了  走吧
I'll leave that to you. Come on.
冠军拍卖行
你见过他吗
You ever seen him before?
没有
No.
停车
Stop.
把车停好  不然我就把你拖着走
Put it in park or I'll drag you across the whole fucking state.
在比林斯的谷仓等我
Meet me at the sale barn in Billings.
我抓到他了
I got him.
是你一个人干的吗
Did you do this alone?
是的
Oh, yeah.
告诉我名字和地址
I want a name and an address.
如果你再骗我
And if you lie to me again,
我下手就不会这么轻了
I'm gonna stop hitting you and start beating you.
明白吗
You understand me?
嗯
Yeah.
医生又让你吃牛排了
Doc letting you eat steak again?
我健康状况良好  麦琪
Got a clean bill of health, Maggie.
我想吃什么就吃什么
I can eat whatever the hell I want.
还是三分熟吗
Still like it rare?
嗯  从冰箱拿出来
Yeah, just pull it out of the cooler,
小火烤一下  然后
whisper fire, and...
放进盘子里
put it on my plate.
我不相信巧合
I don't believe in coincidences.
你一点也不蠢
One thing you aren't is stupid.
可你竟敢再次踏入这个州
And you having the audacity to set foot in this state again,
更别说在我旁边的土地上工作了
much-less work on the land beside mine...
我猜你在监狱里的男朋友
My best guess is that your boyfriend in prison
把你的常识都操没了
fucked all the common sense right out of you.
你还有孩子呢  真不错  韦德
Nice to see you have a child who lived, Wade.
但他有你这么一个父亲
He sure drew the short straw
真是倒了八辈子霉
when it came to you for a father, though.
我给了你一份工作
I gave you a job,
一个你余生都可以称之为家的地方
a place to call home for the rest of your life
而你偷了一个牛仔不会偷的东西
and you stole the one thing a fucking cowboy doesn't steal.
现在你还敢来这里
And now you're here.
你也不傻啊
And you ain't stupid.
我来这里是因为我受雇于此
I'm here because I was hired to be here
你也不能事事都顺心吧
and you can not like that all you want.
也许这就是他们雇我的原因吧
Hell, maybe that's the reason they hired me in the first place.
只要你想和熊而不是幼崽摔跤
Anytime you want to wrestle a bear instead of a cub...
你可以选谷仓  约翰
you can pick the barn, John.
我在谷仓后面等你
I'll meet you behind it.
韦德
Wade.
你有属于我的东西
You have something that belongs to me.
来拿啊
Come and get it.
正有此意
I plan to.
真是操了
Oh, shit! Fuck.
今天真他妈倒霉
This fucking day.
喜欢跟我玩是吧
Want to fucking play games with me?
你他妈
You want to fucking...
他看起来好生气
He seems really mad.
这也太暴躁了吧
Like, I mean, wow, that is one mad fucking man right there.
我觉得还是坐在车里最安全
I think inside the truck is the safest place for us.
吉米  把马牵走
Jimmy, put that fucking horse away.
别怪我  我让你做了选择
Hey, don't blame me. I gave you a choice.
有种崩溃的前兆啊
This has a "first chink in the armor" feel to it.
好点了吗
A little better?
还没有
Not yet.
亲爱的  今天过的怎么样
So, dear. How was your day?
很有启发性
Well, my day was illuminating.
过来坐
Come sit with me.
这是什么
What's that?
正确的说法应该是毗邻
The proper term for it would be a juxtaposition.
我听不懂  贝丝
I don't know what that means, Beth.
我知道  宝贝
I know, baby.
瞧瞧
Look at that.
看起来像O型环
Looks like an O-ring.
嗯  你说对了一半
Oh, yeah. You're half-way right.
我觉得你不是喜欢钻石和黄金的"姑娘"
I didn't think you were a diamonds and gold kinda girl.
明白我的意思吗
Know what I mean?
嗯
Yep.
我不需要礼物  贝丝
Well, I don't need presents, Beth.
我只要你
Just you.
我就是这个意思
Well, that's what it means.
这意味着
It means that you...
我是你的人了
that you have me, that I'm yours.
这意味着"和我一起生活吧"
It means "come live your life with me,"
我只求你能活得比我久
and the only thing I ask is you outlive me
这样我就不用过上没有你的日子了
so I never have to live another day without you.
我可以试试
I can try and do that.
好吧
Okay.
就这么定了
It's settled.
我们结婚吧
We're getting married.
结婚
Married, huh?
是啊  宝贝  我在向你求婚
Yeah, baby. I'm asking you to marry me.
你愿意吗
Will you do that?
我
I mean, I...
我得问问你父亲
I would have to ask your father, though.
我已经摆平了
It's handled.
省得你尴尬
I spared you the indignity.
你意下如何
So what do you say?
我吧
I mean I...
其实我还挺喜欢钻石的
I woulda liked some diamonds, actually.
所以是同意了吗
Is that a yes?
贝丝  我不能去法院
Beth, I can't go to no courthouse.
这个星球上甚至没有我存在的记录
There's no record I even exist on this planet.
是啊
Yeah, well,
结婚证只是一份合同
a marriage license, that's just a contract.
好吗  只能算一笔生意
Okay? That's just business.
咱俩这不能叫生意
We ain't going into business together.
所以想跟我结婚
So marriage to me is...
就带我去那些山的脚下
you take me in front of those mountains.
在我家人和朋友面前
In front of my family. My friends.
我没有朋友  但如果我交了一个
I don't have any friends, but should I make one,
你就要站在我朋友的面前
you would stand in front of them
告诉他们  以后没有你我
and you would tell them there is no more you and I.
只有我们
There's only us.
没问题
I can do that.
-是吗  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-看到烙印了吗  -嗯
- See the brands? - I did.
牲畜委员会探员  开门
Livestock officer, open up.
开门
Open the door.
注意前门  我去后门
Watch the front. I'll take the back.
离墙远一点
Get off the wall.
-什么  -离墙远一点
- What? - Get off the fucking wall.
胸口对着墙
Turn your chest to the wall.
死不了吧
You gonna live?
这就是为什么我让你把胸口对着墙
That's why I told you to turn your chest to the wall.
如果击中你的侧身
If that had hit you in the side
我们就只能用铲子把你装进尸袋
we'd be scooping you into a body bag with a shovel...
说的可真他妈详细
That's... Pretty fucking descriptive.
-能起来吗  还没完事呢  -能
- Can you get up? We ain't done. - Yeah.
我想叫救护车  但我拿不到无线电  凯斯
I'd call for EMS, but I can't reach for my radio, Kacey.
没事  过来  过来  慢慢后退
It's okay, come here. Come here. Back slow.
调度中心  这里是110  情况紧急
Dispatch, this is one-one-zero, Code 3.
两名警官受伤  多处枪伤
Two officers down, multiple GSW.
派救护车和所有可用警力到我的位置
Send EMS and all available units to my 20.
收到  110
Copy one-one-zero.
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You all right, man? - Yeah.
-别动  -如果位置有变  请提前告知
- Just stay still. - Please advise if your 20 has changed.
位置不变
Twenty is the same.
你总说凡事要讲真相
You always preached the truth.
你说这是男人的全部
You said it's all a man has.
男人的话
His word.
就是评判他的标准
Judge him by nothing else.
你自己有不同的评判标准吗
Are there different rules for judging you?
还是有我不知道的真相定义
Or is some other definition of truth that I'm unaware of?
你知道真相和它的含义
You know the truth and what it means.
我不知道真相
All right, I don't know the truth.
我只知道谎言
I just know lies.
我知道你每天都在骗我的谎言
I know the lie you told me every day of my life.
更糟的是  前提是还有更糟的话
And worse, if that's possible,
这还是你让我对你撒的谎
the lie you had me tell you.
我的一生都在撒谎
Every. Day. Of my life.
什么谎言  儿子
What lie is that, Son?
这个  这就是谎言
That. That's the lie.
你叫我儿子  你让我叫你父亲
You called me son, and you made me call you father.
坐下来
Sit down.
你不能再对我指手画脚了
You don't get to tell me what do to anymore--
那就滚出我家
Then get the FUCK out of my house.
你可以坐在我家客厅  也可以离开
You can sit in my living room or you can leave it.
这是你的选择
Those are your options.
公牛给母牛授精后  幼崽并不是它的儿子
When a bull breeds a cow, we don't call the calf its son.
公牛是雄性亲畜  幼崽是它的后代
The bull is the sire. The calf is its offspring.
仅此而已
That's all.
母牛是幼崽的母亲
The cow, well, she... she is the mother.
因为它养育  保护
Because she fed it. Protected it.
关心  爱护幼崽
Cared for it. Loved it.
它配得上母亲的称呼
She deserves to be called mother.
但是公牛
But the bull... He's...
它只是一头公牛
He's just a bull.
永远都只是一头公牛
That's all. And that's all he'll ever be.
你妈妈没有机会爱护你
Your mother never got a chance to love you.
你三个月大的时候  你父亲就用淋浴喷头
You were three months old when he beat her to death
把她打死了
with a shower head.
那个爱护你  养育你
The woman who loved you and fed you
保护你的女人是我的妻子
and protected you was my wife.
还有我
And me.
我保护你  教导你  指引你
I protected you. I taught you. I guided you.
我给予了你父爱和仁慈
I gave you love and kindness and everything your future
还有你未来注定要失去的一切
was guaranteed to be without.
你想怎么叫我都可以  杰米  但是
So you can call me whatever you want, Jamie. But
我还是会叫你儿子
I will call you son
因为我赢得了这个权利
because I have earned the right.
赢得这个权利是我这辈子最艰难的尝试
And earning it has been the hardest thing I've ever done.
你认识他吗
Did you know him?
我认识
Yeah, I knew him.
当他娶了你的生母
And when he married the woman who gave birth to you...
我们都求她不要这么做  因为我们知道结局
We all begged her not to do it because we knew.
但她可能以为自己能拯救他
But I guess she thought she could save him.
我不知道她一开始为什么要这么做
Why she wanted to bother in the first place, I don't know.
我不知道该怎么解释异性的吸引
I don't know how to explain the chemistry of attraction.
为什么它会驱使我们去做会害死我们的事
The thing that drives us to do the very thing that will kill us.
我没法跟你解释
I can't explain it to you,
因为我自己也不明白
because I don't understand it myself.
但你的处境很特殊  杰米
But you are in a unique position, Jamie.
几乎每个人都有过这样或那样的经历
Pretty much everyone at one point or another,
不管是生气还是好奇
whether just mad or curious,
都想知道换个父母的生活会有什么不同
wonders what life would be like with different parents.
但你真的有机会做出选择
You actually have the opportunity to choose.
你很神通广大  儿子
You're a resourceful man, Son.
如果他还活着  你肯定能找到他
So, if he's still alive I'm sure you can find him.
你可以看看他那颗黑心
And you can look into his black fucking heart.
他腐烂的
His rotten...
你可以看着他的眼睛做出选择  杰米
You can look into his eyes, Jamie, and you get to choose.
你可以选择叫谁父亲
You can choose who you call father.
靠  我累了
Goddamn, I'm tired.
在我的灵魂里  我仍然感到年轻
In my soul, I still feel young.
在这里  我感觉自己16岁
In here, I feel sixteen.
在我心里  我觉得
In my heart, I just feel...
太累了
so damn tired.
我从没想过在我还有力气的时候
I never thought I'd be tired of living
我会厌倦生活
while I was still strong enough to do it.
晚安  儿子
Goodnight, Son.